ELEANOR MEARS

DÉVELOPPEMENT WEB & COMMUNICATION

Journaliste de formation et aujourd'hui développeuse front-end, je conçois des sites web à la fois esthétiques, intuitifs et performants. Grâce à plus de dix ans d'expérience dans les médias, j'ai acquis d'excellentes compétences en communication et en gestion de projet. Curieuse, proactive et créative, je suis prête à relever de nouveaux défis dans le secteur du numérique.

CONTACT

+32 467 66 25 44



eleanor.mears@gmail.com



https://eleanor-mears.com

FORMATIONS

REACT DEVELOPER

W₃Schools

2023

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Interface3, Bruxelles

2022 - 2023

JOURNALISME, MASTER OBTENU **AVEC GRANDE DISTINCTION**

Université de Sheffield

2013 - 2014

LITTÉRATURE ANGLAISE ET ALLEMANDE, BACHELIER **OBTENU AVEC DISTINCTION**

Universite d'Oxford

2003 - 2007

COMPÉTENCES

HTML PHP / MySQL

WordPress CSS / SCSS

Elementor Pro Bootstrap

Tailwind CSS Adobe XD **JavaScript** Illustrator Photoshop React

Git Premiere Pro

Node.js **SEO**

LANGUES

Anglais - langue maternelle (C2) /

Français (C1) / Allemand (C1) /

Mandarin (B1) / Néerlandais (A2)

PARCOURS PROFESSIONNEL

CHARGÉE DE COMMUNICATION

Child Friendly Justice European Network, Bruxelles 2024

DÉVELOPPEUSE WEB

ACT Alliance EU. Bruxelles

2023

- Conception et développement d'un site web WordPress
- Utilisation d'outils tels que Google Site Console, Ubersuggest et AIOSEO pour renforcer la visibilité et optimiser les aspects techniques et sémantiques du référencement

DÉVELOPPEUSE WEB (STAGE)

Community Kitchen ASBL, Bruxelles

2023

Conception et gestion d'un site web Wordpress

JOURNALISTE SPÉCIALISÉE DANS LE COMMERCE

Politico, Bruxelles

2020 - 2021

- Interviews
- Rédaction d'articles
- Constitution et entretien d'un réseau professionnel

PRODUCTRICE (TV/WEB)

Deutsche Welle, Bruxelles

2018 - 2020

- Coordination et planification du tournage, du montage et de la post-production d'émissions
- Révision et rédaction de scripts pour les séries TV et web
- Tournage et montage video

RÉDACTRICE EN CHEF. IPS MAGAZINE

Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung, Bruxelles

2016 - 2018

- Conception, rédaction et révision d'articles
- Gestion d'une équipe de reporters, rédacteurs et traducteurs

DÉBUT DE CARRIÈRE

2007 - 2015

Après l'obtention de mon diplôme, j'ai occupé divers postes dans le journalisme et la communication, notamment en tant que stagiaire au Guardian, présentatrice à la International Community Radio Taiwan, et assistante de production à la BBC. En 2015, j'ai déménagé à Bruxelles où j'ai lancé mon activité en tant que journaliste indépendante, couvrant les affaires locales et européennes.

ELEANOR MEARS

WEB DEVELOPMENT & COMMUNICATIONS

JA journalist turned front-end web developer, I bring a passion for crafting websites that are visually engaging, userfriendly and accessible. With over a decade of experience in media, I have developed strong communication and project management skills. I'm proactive, creative, and excited to take on new challenges in the tech world.

CONTACT

+32 467 66 25 44



eleanor.mears@gmail.com



https://eleanor-mears.com

TRAINING

REACT DEVELOPER

W₃Schools

2023

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Interface3, Brussels

2022 - 2023

MASTER OF ARTS IN BROADCAST JOURNALISM (DISTINCTION)

Sheffield University

2013 - 2014

ENGLISH AND GERMAN LITERATURE (2:1)

Oxford University

2003 - 2007

IT SKILLS

HTML PHP / MySQL

WordPress CSS / SCSS

Elementor Pro Bootstrap

Tailwind CSS Adobe XD **JavaScript** Illustrator

Photoshop React

Git Premiere Pro

Node.is **SEO**

LANGUAGES

English - native speaker (C2) /

French (C1) / German (C1) /

Mandarin (B1) / Dutch (A2)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER

Child Friendly Justice European Network, Brussels 2024

WEB DEVELOPER

ACT Alliance EU. Brussels

2023

- Creating and managing a new company website using WordPress, in close collaboration with a team of researchers
- Focus on technical and semantic SEO using tools such as Google Site Console, Ubsersuggest and AIOSEO

WEB DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

Community Kitchen ASBL, Brussels

2023

Creating and managing a new website using Wordpress

TRADE JOURNALIST

Politico, Brussels

2020 - 2021

- Conducting interviews
- Writing/editing news articles and a daily newsletter
- Building a network of contacts

PRODUCER (TV/WEB)

Deutsche Welle, Brussels

2018 - 2020

- Planning and coordinating TV shoots, editing and postproduction.
- · Writing and editing scripts for TV and web videos
- Filming and video editing

EDITOR-IN-CHIEF. IPS MAGASINE

Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung, Brussels

2016 - 2018

- Pitching, writing and editing articles
- Managing a team of reporters, editors and translators

EARLY CAREER

2007 - 2015

After completing my university studies, I ventured into diverse roles within media and communications. These included internships at the Guardian, serving as a news presenter at International Community Radio Taiwan, and contributing as a production assistant at the BBC. In 2015, I relocated to Brussels, Belgium, where I worked as a freelance journalist, covering local and European affairs.